<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>jcperalta</title>
    <link>https://jcacperalta.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on jcperalta</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jcacperalta.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>[TUTORIAL] Which generation controls the Philippine Senate? #DataViz</title>
      <link>https://jcacperalta.github.io/blog/ph-senate-viz/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jcacperalta.github.io/blog/ph-senate-viz/</guid>
      <description>Fork this project in Github here Get the data in Kaggle here  Earlier this year, I saw this post in r/dataisbeautiful showing the representation of generations in the US Senate. After seeing it, I just knew I had to make one for our Senate.
Here is the completed visualization. I based the design from the original post, but the major innovation I made is that I added hover interactions using the python library Bokeh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first (ever) international conference</title>
      <link>https://jcacperalta.github.io/blog/my-first-intl-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 01:17:51 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jcacperalta.github.io/blog/my-first-intl-conference/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m writing this post as I&amp;rsquo;m cramming to finish this site before this year ends. To start this blog, I thought I could share one of my first milestones as an early career researcher&amp;ndash;my first international conference presentation!
This is me presenting our work entitled &amp;ldquo;The Influence of Warmer Sea Surface Temperatures on Southwest Monsoon Rainfall in the Philippines&amp;rdquo; in the Climate Change, Monsoon and Extreme Weather Events session (AS-03-26) of the Asia-Oceania Geosciences Society (AOGS) 11th Annual Meeting in Sapporo, Japan last July 29, 2014.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about me</title>
      <link>https://jcacperalta.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jcacperalta.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Thanks for stopping by!
I am currently a data scientist at the Commercial Operations Division of AC Energy Philippines where I create and deploy market forecasting models and provide weather/climate insights for power trading.
Prior to that, I trained for 6 years as a climate scientist and earned my masters in Atmospheric Science from Ateneo de Manila University last 2019. My topics of interest include regional monsoon dynamics, data validation techniques and climate model evaluation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>my works</title>
      <link>https://jcacperalta.github.io/works/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jcacperalta.github.io/works/</guid>
      <description>An overview of my publications along with citation metrics can also be found on my Google Scholar profile.
Published Works   Peralta J.C.A.C., Narisma G.T., and Cruz F.T. Validation of High-Resolution Gridded Rainfall Datasets for Climate Applications in the Philippines, Journal of Hydrometeorology 21, 7 (2020): 1571-1587, accessed Dec 30, 2020, https://doi.org/10.1175/JHM-D-19-0276.1
  Peralta J.A., Lim M., and Reyes R., Transportation network efficiency during disaster events, Proceedings of the Samahang Pisika ng Pilipinas 38, SPP-2020-3C-07 (2020) https://proceedings.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
